dymocks.com.au 2018-04-19

# Dymocks FAQ | Privacy & Security Policy

##  Privacy Policy

**Application**  
This privacy policy applies to Dymocks Holdings Pty Limited ACN 008 453 110 and each of its subsidiaries and related bodies corporate (as defined in the Corporations Act 2001 (Cth)) who are collectively referred to as “ **Dymocks** ” in this policy.

**Privacy**  
Dymocks respects your right to privacy under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and is required to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles in respect of the collection of personal information from individuals.

**The information we collect**  
The sort of personal information we might collect from you includes your name, gender, age, address, email address, third party services login (e.g. Facebook, Google+, Microsoft or LinkedIn user names), telephone number, fax number, credit card information, order history and information about your areas of interest. For current and potential employees, we will also collect information including emergency contacts, bank and superannuation accounts and prior employment history.

**Consequence of not providing information**  
You have no obligation to provide personal information which you do not wish to disclose. In some circumstances, however, the failure to disclose personal information may mean that Dymocks is unable to provide you with employment or access to goods or services that require the collection of that information.

**How you can access or correct personal information**  
Dymocks will take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it collects, uses or discloses is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You may request access to the personal information we hold about you by contacting us at [privacy@dymocks.com.au](mailto:privacy@dymocks.com.au). If you believe that the personal information we hold about you is incomplete or inaccurate, then you may ask us to amend it. If you have any questions about our policy, or any complaint regarding treatment of your privacy by us, please contact us at [privacy@dymocks.com.au](mailto:privacy@dymocks.com.au).

**Use of Cookies**  
Our website does not use cookies to collect your personal information. Cookies are only used to complete orders on our site. A 'cookie' is a small file which contains a piece of text identifying your browser to our site. It is quite common for online shopping sites to send such a 'cookie', and its purpose is to tell us that a previous visitor to [www.dymocks.com.au](http://www.dymocks.com.au/) has returned.

**How we use the information**  
The information that you provide to us is generally used to provide goods or services to you. Dymocks may also use your personal information and aggregate it with information from other customers to provide you with better service such as by advising you of new products and services or information which may be of interest to you. You have the right to tell us that you do not want us to send information to you other than for the main purpose for which we have collected your personal information.

For current and potential employees of Dymocks, personal information is used to decide whether to offer employment and to manage the employment relationship. It can also be used to conduct various pre-employment checks.

**Disclosure to third parties**  
Dymocks does not generally disclose personal information to third parties. In some circumstances personal information may be disclosed to third parties who perform services on behalf of Dymocks for the purpose of providing you with goods and services or, in the case of current and potential employees, to assist Dymocks in the management of the employment relationship. Dymocks requires third parties who receive your personal information to comply with Australian Privacy laws. Dymocks does not sell or rent any personal information.

**Storage of Information**  
The personal information obtained by Dymocks is stored electronically on servers either controlled by Dymocks or by its contracted third parties who are also bound to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles.

Dymocks takes measures to ensure your personal information is protected from unauthorised access, loss, misuse, disclosure or alteration. We also take measures to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information when it is no longer required. The types of measures we take vary with the type of information, and how it is collected and stored.

**Overseas storage**  
Most personal information held by Dymocks is held on computer systems located within the Commonwealth of Australia. From time to time information may be stored on servers which are located overseas. When this occurs, Dymocks ensures that the third party web storage provider will not use the information and that they are bound to comply with the Australian Privacy Principles or more stringent standards. The countries in which such servers are located are typically either Singapore or the United States of America.

**Links**  
This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by Dymocks and may differ from the policies from other sites that you may link to from this site. We recommend that you read the privacy policy of any site that you link to from this site.

##  Security Policy

At Dymocks we consider the security of your information to be of paramount importance. We have implemented security measures designed to provide the peace of mind you should expect when purchasing goods over the internet. When you place an order, our secure server uses SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) to connect to our website, which encrypts all the information sent from your PC. The following indicates that you have entered a secure session and will be present when you are requested to enter your credit card details:

  * 1\. The "https" in place of the usual "http" in your browser address box
  * 2\. The small padlock either at the bottom or top of your browser (this will depend on the browser you are using)

SSL (Secure Socket Layer) Certification - Verisign

Dymocks Online also has a current VeriSign certificate, which gives you the peace of mind of knowing that we are a legitimate company, and can provide a secure environment in which you can transact. To view details of our security certificate, please click on the VeriSign logo on the left.

From our website we use a payment gateway called SecurePay. Dymocks Online uses SecurePay's Internet Payment Gateway to provide a secure environment for the authorisation of credit card transactions over the Internet. Confidential information including client credit card details are encrypted the moment they are transmitted from the client's browser to the banking network using industry standard SSL 128-bit RC4 encryption technology.

A client's credit card details are not stored anywhere on the Internet and the only company who has access to this data is the merchant's bank. The bank also sends confirmation information via the same encryption technology back to the client's browser. These secure processes provide clients with peace of mind when purchasing online.
